Morris, James O. Office Files /4055
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James O. Morris Office Files
1906-1979
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Morris, James O.
/4055
11 cubic feet
11 linear ft.
Records (documents).
7980341
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 13, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 23, 2016
Biographical / Historical
James O. Morris (February 8, 1923 June 30, 1985) was professor of industrial and labor relations at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of Hiram College and the University of Michigan, Morris joined the faculty of Cornell University in 1955. In the 1950s and early 1960s, he spent time in Chile as a Fulbright scholar and the ILR School's representative at the University of Chile in Santiago. After his time in Chile, Morris returned to Ithaca and taught in Cornell's Department of Collective Bargaining, Labor Law, and Labor History.
Morris was the author of Conflict within the AFL: A Study of Craft versus Industrial Unionism, 1900-1938 (Ithaca: Cornell, 1958), Elites, Intellectuals and Consensus: A Study of the Social Question and the Industrial Relations Systems in Chile (Ithaca: Cornell, 1966), Bibliography of Industrial Relations in the Railroad Industry (Ithaca: Cornell, 1975), and with Roberto Oyaneder, Afiliacion y finanzas sindicales en Chile, 1932-1959 (Santiago: University of Chile Press, 1966).
Morris served on the editorial board of Labor History and Industrial and Labor Relations Review, and was a founding member of the New York State Labor History Association, a group for which he also served terms as vice president and president.
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor James Morris: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18150
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3018: James O. Morris Papers /4056: James O. Morris Papers /4073: James O. Morris Office Files 5518 AV: James O. Morris Collection of Labor Related Tape Recordings 5188m: Association of American Railroads Agreement of May 1936
Morris, James O.
7980341
- NYSSILR Division of International Activities. (Box 1)
  - Division of International Activities (D.I.A.) - Abishegam - Malaysia, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.I.A. - Accion, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - D.I.A. - American Academy of PSS (Political and Social Science), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - D.I.A. - Allowances, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - D.I.A. - Applicants, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D.I.A. - Asia Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - D.I.A. - A.I.D. (Agency for International Development) - Participant Training, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - D.I.A. - A.I.D., 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - D.I.A. - Annual Reports, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - D.I.A. - Attendance at Professional Meeting, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - D.I.A. - Automobile Carnet, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - D.I.A. - 1967-1968 Budget, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - D.I.A. - 1966-1967 Budget, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - D.I.A. - Budget, 1965-1966, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - D.I.A. - Business Office, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - D.I.A. - The Centennial of the First International, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes some French language material; includes news clippings
  - D.I.A. - CIA - Syracuse Herald American, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Includes news clippings
  - D.I.A. - Committee for Economic Development (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Item is a brochure
  - D.I.A. - Coordinator of Research, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - D.I.A. - Copies of Reports, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - D.I.A. - Cost Sharing Policy, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - D.I.A. - Customs Information, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - D.I.A. - Education and World Affairs, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - D.I.A. - Financial Statements, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - D.I.A. - Ford Foundation, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - D.I.A. - Ford Proposal, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - D.I.A. - Cornell-Ford Foundation Terminal Budget, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - D.I.A. - Foreign Students, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - D.I.A. - Friedland Proposal, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - D.I.A. - Fulbright Program, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - D.I.A. - Foreign Visitors, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - D.I.A. - Foreign Visitors 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - D.I.A. - Foreign Visitors 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - D.I.A. - Foreign Visitors 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - D.I.A. - Foreign Visitors 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - D.I.A. - Foreign Visitors 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - D.I.A. - Fund for ISEE (International Social and Economic Education), 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - D.I.A. - Galenson Prospectus, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - D.I.A. - General Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - D.I.A. - Guatemalan Seminar, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Includes some Spanish language material
  - D.I.A. - Ithaca High School Summer Workshop, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - D.I.A. - Institute of International Education, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - D.I.A. - ILR Students from Latin America, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    The dates at the top of the document are mistakenly typed as "Fall 1945 - Spring 1946" instead of the correct "Fall 1965 - Spring 1966"
  - D.I.A. - Income Tax, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - D.I.A. - Inter-American Foundation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - D.I.A. - Inter-American School of ILR and Stycos Interview (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Material is entirely handwritten
  - D.I.A. - Inter-American Social Development Institute, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - D.I.A. - The International Centre for Advanced Technical and Vocational Training in Turin, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - D.I.A. - International Education Act, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - D.I.A. - Japan Project, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - D.I.A. - Kelleher Grant, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - D.I.A. - Henry Landsberger, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- NYSSILR Division of International Activities. (Box 2)
  - D.I.A. - Landsberger Peasant Conference, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - D.I.A. - London Cornell Project (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - D.I.A. - Manpower Development and Training Act, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - D.I.A. - Dean Moore, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - D.I.A. - Margaret Mason, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - D.I.A. - Names of Latinamericanists, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - D.I.A. - National Science Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - D.I.A. - NILE (National Institute of Labor Education), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    January, 1965
  - D.I.A. - NIMH (National Institute of Mental Health), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - D.I.A. - OAS (Organization of American States - 1971 Caracas Conference, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - D.I.A. - OAS - Department of Social Affairs, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - D.I.A. - OAS Per Diem Rates, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - D.I.A. - Overhead Rates, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    August 5, 1966
  - D.I.A. - OES (Overseas Educational Service) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - D.I.A. - Overseas Carriers, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - D.I.A. - Plan Camelot, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Includes mostly Spanish language material; includes architectural prints
  - D.I.A. - Conference at Planting Fields, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Includes some French language material
  - D.I.A. - Potential Staff, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - D.I.A. - Procedure for Research Proposals, 1956-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - D.I.A. - Proposed Inter-American School, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - D.I.A. - Risley, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - D.I.A. - Sabbatic Leaves, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - D.I.A. - Sears, Roebuck, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - D.I.A. - Secretary, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - D.I.A. - Neil Soslow, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - D.I.A. - Spain, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Includes a postcard from Madrid (the letter itself is in English
  - D.I.A. - SSRC (Social Science Research Council) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - D.I.A. - State University of New York, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - D.I.A. - State University of New York - International Studies within the University Faculty Senate Subcommittee, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    March 9, 1967
  - D.I.A. - Summer Salary Support, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - D.I.A. - Translations (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - D.I.A. - Travel Matters - Passports, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - D.I.A. - Traveling Fellowships, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - D.I.A. - Trip - Guatemala, Costa Rica, Panama 1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Item is a small notepad filled with handwritten notes
  - D.I.A. - Villa Jones, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Includes news clipping
  - D.I.A. - Visas and Student Employment, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - D.I.A. - Whyte - Peru Project, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - D.I.A. - John Windmuller, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Windmuller, John, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - D.I.A. - Colombia - Dean Correal, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Includes mostly Spanish language material
  - D.I.A. - Colombia - Morales, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Entirely Spanish language material; includes a handwritten letter and its envelope
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Adams, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Committee on International Activities, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Financial Statements, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Ford Foundation - Robert Bunnell, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Ford Foundation, India, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Ford Foundation - Tax Policy and Allowances, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Institute of International Education, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Millen, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Original Agreement, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Reevaluation, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Shri Ram Center (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Doris Stevenson, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Trip, 1965, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - D.I.A. - India Project - Windmuller, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Audit, 1965, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    January 1, 1965 to March 31, 1966
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Adelaide Barela, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Includes some Spanish language material; includes news clippings
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Balance Statements, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Budget, 1965, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Budget, 1964, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Cornell Financial Statements, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- NYSSILR Division of International Activities; AID - Chile Project Files. (Box 3)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico Program, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Evaluation, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - FEO Names and Addresses (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Entirely Spanish language material
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Final Evaluation Report, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    August, 1966
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - FITPAS (Federacion Internacional de Trabajadores de Plantaciones Agricolas y Similares), 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    English translation is International Federation of Plantation, Agricultural and Allied Workers (IFPAAW); includes some Spanish language material
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Ford Foundation, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    June 3, 1964
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Victor Garcia, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Girard Evaluation, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Item is a note that the original file was too large to fit in a folder; the whereabouts of the original file are unknown
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Dawn Girard, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Lois Gray, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    October 30, 1964
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Interamerican Federation of Working Newspapermen's' Organizations (IAFWNO), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - International Federation of Commercial, Clerical and Technical Employees (IFCCTE), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - International Federation of Petroleum and Chemical Workers (IFPCW), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - International Federation of Plantation, Agricultural and Allied Workers (IFPAAW), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    November 23, 1964
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - International Transport Workers Federation (ITF), 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine and Furniture Workers (IUE), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - International Union of Food Workers (IUF), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Library Project, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Marrero, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Margaret Mason, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Includes two memos to Doris Stevenson
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Marshall Foundation (Oscar Neuhaus), 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Moore, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - New Program Proposal, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Nazario, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Organizational Chart, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Perez Mayol, Salvador - Carlos Roca, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Public Services International (PSI), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Professional Technical Training Institute (PTTI), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Report 1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Risley, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    July 13, 1964
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Union Internacional de Alimentos Afines y Similares (UITA), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - University of Puerto Rico Financial Statements, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Agency for International Development (AID) - Director, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Item is a news clipping dated November 10, 1962
  - AID - Labor Advisory Committee (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Entirely handwritten material
  - AID - University Contract, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    June 30, 1962
  - AID - Accident and Health Insurance, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Budget, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - AID - Budget, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Bell, David - Administrator, AID, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Chile - AID - Contract, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - AID - Contracts and Contract Guides, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Brownell, Ann, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Contract University Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Chile - AID - Mary B. Craig, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Dollar Purchases, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    September 1, 1962
  - Chile - AID/ Washington - Expenditures, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Chile - AID/ Washington - Forms 85 and 86 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - D.I.A. - Puerto Rico - Miles Galvin, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Income Tax, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Chile - AID - Internal Finance, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - AID - Internal Finances, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Chile - Institute for International Services, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Chile - AID - International Training Division, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - AID - Lois Gray Report, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Language Tests, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Kellenbenz, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Chile - AID - Joshua Levine, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Chile - AID - Marking Instructions (Box 3, Folder 58)
    Includes several stickers/patches
  - Chile - AID - Miscellaneous Regulations, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- AID - Chile Project Files. (Box 4)
  - Chile - AID - Monthly Reports of Participants in U.S. and forms, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chile - AID - Thomas J. O'Brien, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Participants - Grades, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chile - AID 0 Participants Handbook, Identity Card, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chile - AID - Participant Training, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Participants - Supplementary Instruction, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Per Diem, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    October 22, 1963
  - Chile - AID - Publicity, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Includes news clippings; includes six black and white photographs
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Standard University Contract, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Tragen, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Semi-Annual Reports, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chile - AID/Washington - Transportation Division, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chile- AID - Visa Renewal, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chile - AID - J.C. Watkins, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    March 9, 1965
  - Chile - ILR Participants - U.S. Travel, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Chile - ILR School Participants - Tuition and Fees, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    September 21, 1962
  - Fernando Canitrot, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Gerhard Hempel, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Chile - Cornell - Moore, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chile - Cornell - Bruce Payne, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    May 1, 1964
  - Chile - Cornell - Pipino, Adelio M., 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Chile - Cornell - Arthur Peterson, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    April 29, 1964
  - Chile - Drafts of Semi-Annual Reports, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Chile - Cornell - Financial Statements, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Chile - Cornell - Insurance Policies, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    February 22, 1963
  - Chile - Cornell - Ford Foundation (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Chile - Library, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Includes many ILR School book plates; includes some Spanish language material
  - Chile - List of Publications, Translations and Research in Progress, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Some book titles on the list are in Spanish
  - Peter Gregory, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - List C - Books for Purchase - Chilean Project (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Chile - Landsberger Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Chile - Landsberger Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Chile - Cornell - Margaret Mason, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Chile - Publications, 1965-1966, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Chile - Cornell - Morris Talks with Insora, September 1965 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    September 9, 1965; entirely handwritten material
  - Juan Iampaglia, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Chile - Cornell - Workmen's Compensation, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    November 27, 1962
  - Discussions with Landsberger, September 1962 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Lois Gray, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Beryl Frank, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Chile - University of Chile - Discussion, December 1964 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Chile - University of Chile - Ford Foundation Proposal (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Folder seems to contain a duplicate of the item in Folder 26 of this box (and contains nothing else)
  - Talks with Ide, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Chile - University of Chile - Molina, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Chile - University of Chile - Seminar Bills, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Department of Labor Relations (DLR) - Armstrong, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Chile - DLR - Manuel Barrera, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    Includes a postcard, written in Spanish, with a black and white photograph as its front; includes some other Spanish language material
  - Department of Labor Relations - Barria, 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Chile - Boroschek, Gunther B., 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Chile - DLR - Butelmann, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - DLR - Dastres, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- AID - Chile Project Files and Reports. (Box 5)
  - Chile - Department of Industrial Relations (DLR) - Department Budget, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Item is handwritten
  - Chile - DLR - Extension, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes one black and white photograph; includes some Spanish language material
  - Chile - DLR - Gonzalez, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - DLR - Jorge Ide, 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes two black and white photographs; includes some Spanish language material
  - Chile - Jeanneret, Andres, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    May 9, 1966
  - Chile - DLR - Labor Relations Course Outline, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chile - Claudio Fuchs, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - DLR - Minutes of Departmental Meeting, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chile - Morgado, Emilio, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - DLR - Oyaneder, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Chile - DLR - Luis Santibanez, 1964-1968 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Report on Labor Extension Activities by Lois S. Gray - Cornell/AID Contract Number ICAc-1197 (Chile), 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    September, 1963
  - Report of Advisory Services Provided to INSORA Faculty of Economics, University of Chile, by Beryl Frank, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    April 7, 1964
  - Report on the Library Program of the Department of Labor Relations of INSORA, by J.G. Miller, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    January 15, 1962
  - Cornell University-University of Chile Library Project - Shipment Number 1, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    July 1, 1963; some book titles on the shipment list are in Spanish or French
  - Cornell University-University of Chile Library Project - Shipment Number 2, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    August 19, 1963; some book titles on the shipment list are in Spanish, French, or Italian
  - Cornell University-University of Chile Library Project - Shipment Number 3, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    October 30, 1963; some book titles on the shipment list are in Spanish, French, Italian, or Portuguese
  - Cornell University-University of Chile Library Project - Shipment Number 4, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    December 6, 1963; some book titles on the shipment list are in Spanish, French, Italian, or Portuguese
  - Cornell University-University of Chile Library Project - Shipment Number 5, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    January 1, 1964; some book titles on the shipment list are in Spanish, French, or Italian
  - Cornell University-University of Chile Library Project - Shipment Number 6, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    January 27, 1964; some book titles on the shipment list are in Spanish
  - Cornell University-University of Chile Library Project - Shipment Number 7, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    October 12, 1965; some book titles on the shipment list are in Spanish or German
  - Periodical List - Cornell University-University of Chile for INSORA Biblioteca, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    October 1, 1963; some titles on the list are in Spanish
  - Fifth Report Covering the Period December 16, 1961 to June 15, 1962, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Sixth Semi-Annual Report - Extra Copies, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    June 16, 1962 to January 15, 1963
  - Seventh Semi-Annual Report - Extra Copies, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    January 16, 1963 to July 15, 1963
  - Eight Semi-Annual - July 16, 1963 to January 15, 1964, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Ninth Semi-Annual Report - January 16, 1964 to July 15, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Tenth Semi-Annual Report -July 16, 1964 to January 15, 1965, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 28)